On the same day we launched Nutonic,
I started a business mentorship where I
was
going to help small businesses make a
little bit extra money a month.
Quickly,
nearly done $5.1 million since December
2023, and that works
out to $282,445 a month.
And hopefully Declan
made it look super sexy by putting those
numbers up in the background.
Now I'm going to tell you exactly how I've
done it so you can apply what I use into
your business, your frameworks,
and what you do.
But first,
we have to address how I got here with
this idea for a video in the
first place. Ta-da! Taki Moore. Met him,
great guy.
Nearly caught up with him in Japan.
Nearly caught up with him in LA.
Missed him both times. Due to see him.
And Taki is actually one of my
competitors.
We message every now and then.
I want to do a video with him,
and I've got an hour
till a haircut. I'm going to shave it.
I'm going bald. Shock. Water is wet.
And I was like, what
is his best performing video?
And it's this title.
So I had to emulate it
and give you a version a little bit more
succinct because we
do things differently. Although actually,
out of all the people online in the
business space,
he's one of the only people that I go,
"Do you know what?
I agree with that." Now just before we get
into it, it's worth mentioning, rev is
not profit. I've had a good chunk of that,
but so have my staff, so has the
Australian Tax Office,
so Shaan at Gemflow.
But what this has done,
and I'll be honest,
it's given me a bump in revenue every
month that I can just enjoy myself with
because my coaching app, James Smith
Academy, pays my bills, pays my mortgage,
covers most of my things that I need in
life, pays my pension, whatever.
This business on the side gives me fun
tokens, which I built this studio with.
And just before I put this marker to good
use, again, I just want to reiterate, I'm
not here to make you a millionaire.
I'm here to make you an extra two grand a
month. Two grand a month for you.
Less worry about the mortgage.
Start planning that holiday you
were supposed to go
on last year.
Maybe even get your partner to stop
working, whatever it is.
That to me is the magic.
So as you can see here,
I only watched a little bit of
Taki's video. Let's get into it.
There's going to be a link in the
description.
I'm doing a three-day free live webinar.
We're going to cover three pillars:
content, leads, money. Register for it.
Come along. Just by signing up, even
if you can't attend,
I'll send you the videos
once we've done them.
You can sit through them completely free,
no hidden charges.
So please click that link and register.
All right.
Now, although there
are a lot of people on the internet
that make more money than
me, including Taki,
the impressive thing isn't to me the 200K
I'm making a month,
it's the fact that I've averaged
that over two years.
And for that to happen,
you have to have processes in place.
That means you don't burn out.
You have to enjoy what you're doing.
For instance, the reason
that I don't use sales calls, same as him,
wasn't even
efficiency, it was enjoyability.
And also the elephant in the room is
if I'm going to get someone to close sales
calls because I'm not going to do it,
I could be doing better things,
going to have
to give them 10% of that.
So they're incentivized to close, which
is good from a
sales perspective, but I can't help
but feel that can attract people
that maybe
aren't perfect for the course.
And I'll give you an example.
When I was younger
and I used to invite girls to go on dates,
if at any point I
realized that we weren't really right for
each other, rather than forcing it, I
would just leave it. For instance,
in Bondi, during winter,
I would ask girls if
they wanted to go for a swim in the sea,
and if they were like, "What do you mean?
It's bloody winter.
The water's cold." Rather than going, "Oh,
we'll just go on a
date instead." I knew I got a signal very
early on that they weren't right for me.
So this process, this funnel
that I'm about to go through, there
are so many
different opportunities in
that process for them to opt out,
to never make it to
the sales page or to never make it into
the mentorship because you need to be very
selective with who it is
that you want to work with because you got
to work with
them. So I had to start from scratch.
Created a YouTube and an Instagram.
I knew one which did confuse a lot of
people.
Now I think these work synergistically.
I'm going to explain the benefits now.
Instagram is easy to create content.
You just pick up your phone and you shoot.
YouTube has a much better way of getting
an average view duration.
So although this is easier, people
are going to watch for maybe 60 seconds to
a
minute,
and you've still got to win over
that view algorithmically.
Here, if you win someone over,
for instance, you're watching now,
the amount of
time they're spending watching you
is going to increase.
I think that has a massive benefit to the
bond you can build with someone, not to
mention trust. Instagram benefits,
you can create a lot of volume of content.
You can do one a day very easily.
YouTube is a little bit more difficult.
Some of my best performing videos on this
YouTube channel are evergreen.
They're over a year old,
and they're still churning in leads on an
ongoing basis.
So although it's easier to put volume on
Instagram, I think the fact that you can
have videos that generate you leads for
years on end, that's great.
Chatbots are an incredibly powerful tool,
which we'll get into in a second.
But then I think the call to actions
that you can do on long form
are always going
to be that little bit easier.
So for instance,
when I told you about the three-day
webinar before,
I could kind of sell it to you.
Remember I did the hook, the introduction,
then just before we're going into the
kind of payoff of the video, I got
that in there.
You'll also notice I've started wearing
microphones under the shirt.
I got like a magnetic necklace.
I'm not a guy that likes jewelry,
but I always had
a gripe with the magnet sitting there on
the front. So there you go.
So when we look at this,
we want to look at this as an organic
content
machine. Now,
you must master this first because ads
is the icing on the
cake that you put on top of this.
You can clip a lot of this for ads,
but also you
can look at the best performance from this
so you know what to do for ads.
Now, I would say on any given month,
30% to 40% of revenue goes in
ads,
which is kind of depressing because this
month we've done about 100K.
And you might go, "Oh my God,
100K." I know 40K of that
is already in ads.
So now I'm left to 60. Shaan,
whose platform I use,
he's getting his cut.
Now I'm down to 50.
My manager's always going to get 20%,
so that's 40.
Not to mention staff, bills, costs,
whatever it is.
So I need to make 100K to keep the lights
on. No, I don't get the MRs.
We'll negotiate that.
So we've got all of these people through
ads and the organic
content machine watching content,
enjoying it.
We're building a relationship.
The next thing we need to do from here
isn't send them to a sales call, in my
opinion.
I think the best thing we can do from here
is get some form of data.
And you guys know I love email addresses.
So my chatbots will send people to a
squeeze page, like a page that
is designed to
get their email address with a call to
action will send them there.
And if we can get their data,
specifically an email,
I like to put them through a
little automation. And what that means
is once they sign up, I'm just going to
pre-write some emails
that go out every day just to nurture them
and make them feel
like I'm an authority in this space.
Of course,
I'm going to be putting in an offer for
these to buy from me.
But again, I would like to think
that at least 50% of people
that join the email
list, even if they never buy,
they get value from it.
Now,
we're now in the second iteration of
Business Mentorship 2.0, which is going
to be shutting down at the end of 2026.
And I'm going to spin up 3.0, which
is going to be completely different.
But this is the main ticket.
There's two current offers for that,
2.5 to
3.5K. So on any given day,
we're going to try
and push people to the business
mentorship and they're going to buy. Cool.
But at the moment,
we're taking a bit of a step back from
this.
So as you will have noticed,
the current offer at the moment
is the three-day
webinar,
which we've called Content Leads Money.
This is, to begin with, just an idea.
We're starting to map it out.
We're starting to build it out.
But ultimately,
we just need something to take
people away from here to there.
And this is almost like a holding company
in a
financial structure because people do get
exhausted going through the same thing.
They're like, "We get it, we get it,
we get it." ThisThis will exhaust just as
much
as the ads will.
So we're going to create this.
We're going to put together the webinar,
like I said.
Now,
I've allocated in paid ads $20,000 because
I know
we need that data. Not to mention
that when we do the event, we
are going to use
all the existing data we already have.
All those people
that have gone through automations
and maybe not even bought,
they're going to be pushed into this.
Because even if someone has come down into
the funnel and they're over here
somewhere,
we can always bring them back because it
might just be a little bit more
information that they need before they get
closed.
Or it's not always information
that people need.
Sometimes I'm a really strong believer
that there is an emotional position
that you
get to with someone where you've helped
them enough that they're just, "Take my
money." Take my money because you've
helped me so much for free,
I might as well be
a part of your paid program.
So all of my marketing direction funnels
at the moment
are actually going away from this.
And you'll notice
that one of the things that I've done
is I'm increasing the
volume of the videos that are going out.
Because everything's building towards
here, so we can do the three-day event,
and
we can bring people into the business
mentorship. Now,
that's what I'm doing now.
Some of the other things
that I'd recommend for you guys is this.
Once you're building this out
and you have people coming through to your
offer,
first thing you want to do
is make sure that you price it in the
right amount.
So when this began, this was $800.
It's now at 2.5 to 3K. What happened?
We got more people in
that organic content machine.
We got to bump up the price because of
that.
Any of you that are going to start out,
start low. You can always raise prices.
It's very difficult to bring them down
once you've got going.
Now,
when you work with people with inside your
program, whatever it is, you're
going to realize
that people have got frequent
and common needs between them.
So for instance, we found out content
was one of the pillars that people needed
help with the most. So therefore,
we doubled down on it.
So my, quote-unquote,
"satellite courses," Short-Form Content
Mastery, Send
Emails, Get Paid. So a play button,
et cetera.
By building these out, it meant
that we were adding an artillery of more
resources
for people within the mentorship.
But at the same time,
these could also be used as single one-off
products that
could go into people in
that queue in the automation, people
that had said, "I'm
interested," but they hadn't bought yet.
This meant that some people could then go
into the shorter courses.
Their ticket level to come in could be,
say, $99.
And then from Short-Form Content Mastery,
for instance, we had a 6% upsell into the
business mentorship. Now, any of you
that have done Short-Form Content Mastery,
just to let you know,
I'm about to refilm the whole thing
and add so much more,
including AI.
So if you have paid $99 for that already,
I'm about to replace the
entire thing for free.
Because you guys are legends
and you propped me up and
supported me over the last few years,
I'm going to be doing that.
And by the way,
everyone that's ever bought from me,
when this goes to 3.0,
everyone that had 2.0 will be given it.
Same way that everyone
that had 1.0 got 2.0, et cetera.
Once you're in, you're in.
Some of my biggest ever clients only paid
me $800.
Now,
some of you are probably wondering why I
set a one-off price and
not a subscription or anything like that.
And the reason for that being is
that with everything we sell,
there's going to be
something called an average customer
value.
How much does the average person spend
with us?
Now, for any of you out there,
let's say you're a personal trainer
or a fitness
coach and you charge 100 pounds a month,
and the average person stays with you for
six months, your average customer value
is 600 pounds.
So then if you created a product that
was 650 that was six months long, you'd be
able to sell something
that increased your average customer
value.
Now,
the reason that I like it being a one-off
price and lifetime access is that,
first of all,
it doesn't rush people too much to go
through the modules of the
course or whatever.
And then I can just limit the amount of
time they're in the
Discord, so again,
they're not felt rushed,
but they can go through the Discord at
their own time. The main reason is
that I can control the average value of a
customer to me by increasing the prices.
Rather than trying to tie people in with
contracts or saying, "You've got to stay
for 12 months," or whatever it is,
I just set a price that I'd be happy with.
So when I work with someone,
I like to deliver to them that value.
Now, for some people,
that's a lot of hand-holding in the
Discord.
It's a lot of help. But for others,
Ali McLean, for instance, had to say
this about working with me in the
mentorship.
When I started your business mentorship,
I had 60,000 followers.
I wasn't doing shit.
But in a couple of years, I'm now at
on Instagram.
So that's fucking significantly more.
But on Facebook, I've gone from 5,000 to
247,000.
And that's because of your advice.
It's because of picking a niche,
changing it,
making people know what I actually do.
Because I remember messaging you saying,
"Oh, James, yeah, I do this.
This is my problem."
And you ignored my question and went,
"Listen, I've watched
your videos.
I have no fucking idea what you coach."
[chuckles] And I was going,
"That's a good point because I don't
actually teach MMA fighters."
And it made me
go down the route of reaction.
So big thank you to you.
For Ali,
one of the most important things for his
business was me saying to him,
"Bro, I watch your stuff.
I don't know what you're selling." To him,
that was worth
more than the ticket price. Some people,
when they join the Discord, I'm like,
"Hey,
I don't understand what you sell."
And the problem is that even when they
join and they introduce themselves to me
and tell me what they do, if I don't know
what they're doing,
then their audience doesn't either.
So anyway, the reason
that I charge what I do
is I want to control the average
customer value. And those of you
that do join the mentorship,
if within three to
six months you haven't got your investment
back, just email me, james@newtonic.com,
because I would much rather we didn't have
bad blood between us.
That 5 million I made could be 10 million
if I was a bit more of a Nazi, but I'm
not. I like to sleep well at night.
So this time last year, we were cooking,
and the reason for that is
that once you're creating a lot of content
like this and
you're spending a lot of time with people
here, you can create events.
Now, the exciting thing about events
is this.
You can get in person to meet
and spend time with the person that
you watch online.
Because for all you know,
I could be here just reading a
teleprompter the whole time. I'm not.
But going to an event,
you get to spend time with people.
They get to read your energy.
Sometimes you get to really understand
what someone's
like just by watching their human
interaction with people.
Some people can be fake, and some people,
when you meet them in real life, are just
not what you're expecting.
So the in-person events work well because,
well, let me
teach you exactly how I do it.
So we have an event coming up towards the
end of the
year in London. So what you do
is you have a venue, and let's say that
is 30K.
Then how many seats?
Let's say you got 1,000 seats.
You could then sell tickets at 30 pounds.
Boom,
you're going to make your money back on
the venue.
Then anyone that upsells from
that event is where you make a profit
margin.
Or you could decide to make it 300 pounds
per ticket.
You get 1,000 people, you make 300K.
Or you can make the ticket price 300.
You sell 1,000. You make 300K.
You make a 10X.
But I think it's going to be easier to do
that through this mechanism than
anything else.
Because at least then people can work with
you for a bit more time,
et cetera. Looking at that, though,
those numbers are quite nice.
300K would be nice, wouldn't it? Oh, God,
yeah.
And then you'd run ads into that event.
You do the event,
you get people into the business
mentorship.
But again, people that don't join,
you would then send into your data.
They might go into an automation,
and you might be able to make $99 back
if they go
into a satellite course.
So this ecosystem already exists.
Now, one of the good things is
when I record this video,
I'm going to send it to
Declan. Declan gets the video,
and he edits it. So me,
Declan gets the edit.
Now, when Declan's edited it,
it goes to Ollie.
Now,
Ollie is also working within my mentorship
to help people do YouTube.
I also know that Crafty little fuckers
probably doing one-to-one with people, but
that's fine. So once Ollie gets
that video,
he then optimizes it for YouTube.
All the titles and thumbnails at the
moment are Ollie. I will oversee that.
I'll take a little bit of a look. Now,
Declan won't mind me saying this.
I don't have monetization on for this
channel, but any videos
that he does for the
main channel, I give him 10% of rev.
But I do limit it to the first month.
The reason I do that is I want
that video to come out the gates firing.
Now, Ollie, for YouTube,
where we have the links in the
description, I give him a
percentage,
I can't actually remember what it is,
of the revenue from each video.
So the reason is
that I incentivize Declan to make good
videos for the main channel
because he's getting money.
I incentivize Ollie because then
if Ollie puts in a
killer title and thumbnail,
that's going to increase the amount of
conversions,
average view duration, visits, whatever.
Then the people that click on average from
a video, he's going to get
incentivization for that.
I need to incentivize this cohort of
people to
make sure that this part works well.
There's also Cam and Jayden.
I nearly forgot his surname then.
And these guys are really the marketing
brain
power of the business as well. These guys,
rather than having a sales team, they're
going to pressure people on the call.
I've said to them, these guys
are going to work with everyone inside
here.
They're going to potentially give me ideas
that I can make content for in my
organic content machine. And
if any of those ideas end up coming
through, these
guys, I've offered 10% of any sale
that they make.
Because I would much rather that Cam
or Jayden is working with someone in the
mentorship and they go, "Wow,
Trish has just had this amazing
transformation to her
business." I go, "Hey,
do you reckon you guys could put
that into an email?"
Email gets written,
email goes to the automation,
people get it, they buy in.
It's only fair that
that kickback goes to the brainpower of
the person that got it
in the first place.
Because now I want it to be in a position
that once I finish
recording this video
and I send it to Declan,
everyone gets looked after in the
ecosystem.
And the more I can automate the ads,
the emails, the
events, whatever it is, it means
that my time only needs to be spent in the
organic content machine,
these guys taking care of each other,
and I can spend my
time looking after the people
that pay the bills.
So the reason this business has been able
to generate 200K a month on
average for over two years
is exactly because of this.
Now, the beautiful part of all of this
and the lesson that many of you should
take
for your business is I intentionally don't
want to go viral on my YouTube channel
because I want the people
that watch the videos to be right.
I want the average view duration to be
high.
But if one of these two videos goes
haywire, goes hectic, goes crazy, does
whatever, everything in the ecosystem
is going to be bolstered from it.
Everything is going to triple down.
One video in the YouTube system sets
alight everything, leads, emails,
data, more people to live event,
more people to the physical events,
more people
into these products and offerings here.
Everyone lives good.
And here's one thing that's kind of
unique.
Everyone I employ in
that ecosystem works for me pretty much
because they want to
do their own thing.
And I think they're at a stage in their
life where winning
business is quite difficult,
and I'm quite good at it.
I'm going to win it for them. But Cam,
Jayden, Ollie, Declan are all
growing, and they will fly the nest soon.
They will go do their own thing.
Declan, the cheeky fucker,
he's got 10,000 people on his email list.
Kept that fucking quiet, didn't he?
Kept that fucking quiet.
He's only got 10,000 subscribers.
My golden rule is the 20% of people
that follow you on email. He's got 100%.
Ollie is a dark horse.
I trust him as far as I can throw him.
But that's what I want. The people
that work with me are entrepreneurs
that I want
to do really well,
and I treat my clients
and my mentorship the exact same way I
treat my staff. You want my honest advice?
I'll give it to you.
You want me to tell you where your
business should go? I'll give it to you.
I enjoy this.
I never had a little brother growing up,
and now I've got
thousands of them. Some of them are men,
some of them are women.
I enjoy this for the same reason I enjoyed
personal training.
That's probably why you should pick a
personal trainer as your business coach.
I spent the last 10 years just making sure
that people were getting stronger and
they were feeling good, and they
were happy with the way their life
and their
training was going.
I used to help people get swole.
Now I help their businesses
and their brands and their social media do
it.
If you want to work with me,
there's a link in the description.
If you want to come to
that three-day webinar, 100% come.
Anything else,
just pop a question in the comments below
and I'll get back to you.
Thanks for watching.